有问题吗
Problem?
-这是泰国菜  -又来了
- This is Thai food. - Here we go.
我们周四不吃泰国菜
We don't have Thai food on thursday.
我们吃批萨
We have pizza on thursday.
对  但我们说过每月第三个星期四
Yes, but we all agreed that the third thursday
是一切皆有可能的星期四
At every month would be anything can happen thursday.
显然没有满足我的消化系统要求
Well, apparently that you didn't reach my digestive system
在一切皆有可能的星期四
which when startle has its own version
也有自己的要求
On anything can happen thursday.
拜托  一切皆有可能的星期四
Come on, the whole idea hehind anything can happen thursday
它的含义是摆脱近期的刻板生活
Is to get out this rut we've been in lately.
刻板  你是说连贯性吧
Rut? i think you mean consistency.
如果要废除这个
And if we're going to abandon that,
那干嘛要叫它星期四
Then why even call it thursday?
直接称为狂口日
Let's call it quorncle day,
分为29小时17分钟
And divide it into 29 hours and 17 minutes a piece,
杀鸡宰羊来庆祝 感谢万能的刻板之主
And celebrate it by sacrificing a goat to the mighty god rut.
我同意杀鸡宰羊
I can go for some goat.
谢尔顿  我们说好今晚做点改变
Seldon, we agreed we do something different tonight.
好啊
All right.
我们去漫画书店吧
Let's go to the comic book store.
我们昨晚就去过了
We went to the comic book store last night.
昨天是星期三
Last night was Wednesday
星期三是漫画之夜
Wednesday is comic book night
今天去就是周四去啦
Tonight we will be going on Thursday
因为今天是一切皆有可能的星期四
Because it is Anything Can Happen Thursday
何必出去
Rather then get outside,
在饭盒面前拜神啊  谢尔顿
But praise right up against the box, Sheldon.
我们今晚到底干什么
So what are we gonna do tonight?
听我的建议吧
If I may profer a suggestion
在这个国家广袤的土地上林立着无数个酒吧
in bars, all across this great nation
我们的周四应该是美女之夜
Our Thursday night is Ladies' Night
到了晚上我们就衣冠楚楚倾巢出动
Which means as the evening progresses we will get better looking
99分一杯的玛格丽特
99 cent margaritas
还有买一送一的果子冻饮料
and two-for-one jello shot
拜托  霍华德
Come on Howard,
我们在酒吧泡妞的成功率几乎为零
The odds of us picking up girls at bar is practically zero
你听过德瑞克方程式么
ok, Really, are you familiar the Drake equation
那个用来估算 与外星人接触的概率
The one that estimates the odds making contact with the extraterrestrials
通过计算逐步增加的
By calculating the product of increasing
一系列分数值的乘积
restricted  series of fractional value
比如具有行星的星系
such as external planet
或者有生命存在的行星
and the planet likely to develop life
N=R*Fp*Ne*Fl*Fi*Fc*L
对  就是那个
Yeah, That one.
你可以通过把
you can modify it to calculate our chance of having sex
数据改成洛城单身女人的数量和
by changing the formula to use the number of single women in LA
通过沃罗威茨系数计算出来天仙妹妹数量
and the number of those i find attractive
用来计算我们有爱可做的概率
by what i call the wolowitz coefficient
沃罗威茨系数?
The wolowitz coefficient?
欲望*次数*压力的平方
needing us times stress size square
计数来看
counting the numbers i come
我周围40英里范围内有5812个潜在性伙伴
up with conservative 5812 potential sex partners within a 40miles radius
你开玩笑吧
you're joking.
我是个性饥渴的工程师  莱纳德
i am a horny engineer leonard.
我从不拿数学和性开玩笑
i never joke about math or sex.
那还等什么  俺们快去钓马子
what are we waiting for? lets bounce bitches.
你说得对
oh, you're right.
今天是一切皆有可能的星期四
it's anything can happen thursday
大家去酒吧美眉
let's hit the club and meet hot women.
太对了  看好女儿哦
here we go, lock up your daughter.
不然我们上完可不买账哦
we're going to hit them and quit them.
还是吃完东西去漫画书店吧
or we can finish eating and then go to the comic book store.
也是个好主意
also a good plan.
好吧  但下个一切皆有可能的星期四
all right. but next anything can happen on thursday.
我们一定要去酒吧
we ll definitely go into a bar
当然了
Absolutely.
听见没有  美女们  我们迟早会临幸你们的
You heard that ladies night, ladies we are eventually coming for you.
有意思
Fascinating.
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译制作
更多美剧下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
伙计们  去哪儿
Oh Hey Guys, Where are you heading?
漫画书店
To the comic bookstore.
你可能在想  星期三去漫画书店
You are probably thinking the comic bookstore on a Thursday
明明要掉到兔子洞  怎么就变成迷幻世界了
Why falling down the rabbit hole and into a land of magnet.
如果你没有听懂的话
If you've failed to take into account Penny
今天是一切皆有可能的星期四
This is anything-can-happen-Thursday
被你说对了
You got me.
你们能不能帮我挑几本漫画
Oh hey, while you are there could you pick me up a few comics
给我外甥当生日礼物
for my nephew's birthday?
你说的是漫画书吧
No, I think you mean comic books
漫画只是苍白无力的幽默
comics are feeble attempts humor featuring
搞些说话的小人儿  拟人的宠物
talking babies and anthropomorphized pets
旧时有个乐观的名字叫"开心一刻"
found traditionally in the optimistically named funny pages.
莱纳德能不能帮我挑几本漫画
Leonard can you pick me up a few comics for my nephew's birthday?
好啊  他爱看什么
Sure what does he like?
不晓得  他才13岁  随便挑吧
I don't know. he is thirteen, just pick out anything.
随便挑?
Just pick out anything?
说不定我们能在不知道尺码的情况下
May be the same time we can pick out a new suit for him
给他挑一套新衣服
without knowing his size.
或者在不知道他职业倾向的情况下
or pick out his career form
给他挑一份工作申请表
without knowing his aptitude.
又或者在不知道他膳食纤维需求的情况下
or pick out his breakfast cereal
给他挑一盒早餐麦片
without knowing his fiber requirements
或者他喜不喜欢小软糖
Or his feelings about little marshmallows.
《蜘蛛侠》  给他挑《蜘蛛侠》
Spider-man. get him spider-man.
《神奇蜘蛛侠》  《终极蜘蛛侠》  《惊奇蜘蛛侠》
Amazing spider-man, ultimate spider-man, spectacular spider-man,
《惊险蜘蛛侠》  《蜘蛛侠2099》
The marvelous adventures of spider-man, spider-man 2099?
莱纳德
Leonard?
你知道他会说个没完
You know this can go on all night.
直接跟我们去吧
Why don't you just come with us?
我就是不想跟你们去
That's what I was trying to avoid.
我把《惊叹蜘蛛侠》给忘了
Oh, I forgot sensational spider-man.
多可爱的小店啊
Aw, what a cute, little store.
大家都盯着我
Ev-everybody's staring at me.
别担心  他们比你还惊讶呢
Don't worry, they're more scared of you than you are of them.
咋不像呢
Unlikely.
送这个给我侄子怎么样
Here, what about this one for my nephew?
-眼光一流  -太好了
- A superb choice. - oh, great.
但他必须看过《无限危机》和《52》
Provided he has already read infinite crisis and 52,
还要熟悉DC的多元宇宙重建
And is familiar with the reestablishment of the dc multiverse.
什么是多元宇宙
What's a "multiverse"?
带她出去
Get her out of here.
来吧  我帮你选
Come on, I'll help you pick something.
没错  她和我们是一起的
That's right. she's with us.
这些家伙真可怜
Guys like that are so pathetic.
说说看
Tell me about it.
瞧  新版蝙蝠侠皮带扣哦
Ooh, look, a new batman belt buckle.
好啊  莱纳德
Oh, hey, leonard.
需要帮忙吗
Can I help you find something?
你好  史都华  这是佩妮
Oh, hey, Stuart. this is penny.
她想买几本漫画书
She's just looking for some comic books.
是吗
Oh, really, wow.
如果不是自愿来的  眨两下眼睛
Blink twice if you're here against your will.
还好啦  史都华
I think we're fine, stuart.
需要帮忙就叫我
Okay. well, let me know if you need anything.
谢谢
Thanks.
他人好像挺不错呢
Oh, he seems like a nice guy.
你说喜欢漫画的人吗
You mean for someone who's into comic books?
不  不是
No. no-no-no.
我是说...没错
I just meant for... yeah.
佩妮
Penny,
喜欢漫画不代表就是怪人
Just because people appreciate comic books doesn't make them weirdos.
史都华是个天才艺术家呢
Stuart's a terrific artist.
他在罗德岛学校学过设计
He went to the rhode island school of design.
那那个穿超人T恤
What about the guy over there in the
还塞进运动裤的人呢
Superhero t-shirt tucked into his sweatpants?
那是运动裤船长
Uh, yeah, that's captain sweatpants.
他确实不是我说的那种人
He doesn't really help the point I'm trying to make.
-买过  -买过
- Got it. - got it.
-没买  - 没买
- Need it! - Need it!
放手  谢尔顿
Let it go, sheldon.
为什么  我先看到的
Why should I let go? I saw it first.
但我从正面看到的
Yes, but I saw it from the front.
这算什么伎俩
A far less impressive feat.
拜托
Oh, come on!
我要收藏《蝙蝠侠》系列的
I need this for my batman collection.
我还要收藏《神通罗宾》呢
Well, I need it for my robin collection.
石头剪刀布蜥蜴史波克
Rock-paper-scissors- lizard-spock?
我干嘛要冒险
Why would I gamble?
我的  放手
It's mine. let go.
-你放手  -你放手
- You let go. - no, you!
-你放手  -怎么回事
- No, you! - problem?
他抢我的漫画书
Yes. he won't let go of my comic book.
是我的才对
It's my comic book!
莱纳德  做个裁决
Leonard, we need a ruling.
裁两半吧
Cut it in half?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你好啊
Oh, hello again.
给13岁男孩的礼物  你有什么推荐
Hi. what would you recommend as a present for a 13-year-old boy?
13岁的女孩
A 13-year-old girl.
如果你一定要选漫画的话  试试这个
But if you're dead set on a comic book, try... this.
《地狱神探》
Oh, hellblazer.
讲什么的
What's this about?
一个走在正邪之间  因抽烟患有肺癌
A morally ambiguous confidence man who smokes,
被不死的灵魂折磨着的男人的故事
Has lung cancer and is tormented by the spirits of the undead.
如果这个还不能让我成为最受欢迎阿姨
Well, if that doesn't make me the favorite aunt,
真不知道什么会了
I don't know what will.
这画的是我?
Is this me?
看情况了  你喜欢么
Depends. do you like it?
画的真棒
Wow, it's really good.
没错  就是你
Yes, that's you.
太可爱了  但如果我不喜欢呢
That's so sweet, but what if I didn't like it?
还是你  不过我就是个傻瓜
It'd still be you, but I'd feel like an idiot.
真不敢相信
I don't believe it.
史都华在对佩妮采取行动
Stuart's putting the moves on penny.
我真该学学怎么画画
I have got to learn how to draw.
再一次  你被你的恶趣味打败
Hey! once again, defeated by your own prurient interests.
哥几个  你们有没有发现史都华霸着佩妮不放?
Guys, have you seen stuart all up in penny's business over there?
没人霸着谁
Nobody's up in anybody's business.
买完东西赶紧闪人吧
Let's just buy our stuff and go.
你有我的电话号码了
Okay, you've got my number.
现在  把这幅画给我吧
Now, give me the picture.
你真会砍价
You drive a hard bargain.
给你
But here.
记得打电话给我
All right. so, um, just give me a call.
莱纳德  你现在对"周四夜惊喜"怎么看
So, leonard, how are you enjoying anything can happen thursday?
快看
Look at that.
这有个凹痕
That's a dent.
谢谢  霍华德·"大拳"·沃罗威茨
Thank you, howard "ham-fisted" wolowitz.
你在初版星际旅行"毛球的麻烦"
Did you just shut the tv off in the middle of the classic
播到一半时居然把电视关了?
The original series "trouble with tribbles" crossover episode?
显然是这样的
Apparently so.
你生病了?
Are you ill?
-没有  -好的
- No. - all right.
这么说你就是因为今天早些时候
Then is it fair to say that you're experiencing some sort of
佩妮的事而在生闷气咯
Emotional turmoil over the events involving penny earlier this evening?
你什么时候注意到的?
When did you pick up on that?
就在刚才
A moment ago,
看"毛球的麻烦"[《星际旅行》中的的经典篇章]
When you turned off the tv in the middle of the classic
看到一半把电视关了的时候
The original series "trouble with tribbles" crossover episode.
想听听我的建议么
Would you like some advice?
当然了
Sure, why not?
现在正是你写那种大家可以留言的
Well then,This is the perfect time to launch a
博客的好时机
Blog with an interactive comments section?
真是谢谢你了
Gee, thanks a lot.
你想听听我对此事的看法么
Would you rather I offer my personal insight?
不必了
I don't need any insights.
我只想知道为什么佩妮对史都华比对我感兴趣
I just want to know why penny's more interested in stuart than me.
我们差不多啊
We're practically the same guy.
我不同意
Oh, I disagree.
斯图尔特更高更有才  自己当老板
Stuart is taller, artistic, self-employed and, most significantly,
更重要的是  他买漫画打五五折
He gets 45 percent off comic books.
你说的没错
You're right.
我真该上网寻求陌生人的帮助
I really should be asking strangers on the internet.
我早就说了
My original point.
中国菜  老式游戏
Chinese food, vintage video games...
经历了不可思议的周四的噩梦
After the nightmare of anything can happen thursday,
现在是遵循我所有习惯的周五了
This is friday night the way it was meant to be.
谁同意周六来个无谢尔顿日
Who's up for sheldon-free saturday?
大家好
Oh, hey, guys.
佩妮好  还有史都华
Hey, penny... and stuart.
史都华好
Hey, stuart.
大家好
Hey, guys.
你们哪玩去
So what are you kids up to?
画展有史都华的一幅画  今天正好开幕
Stuart has a piece in an art show that's opening tonight.
你们两个一起去呀  真好
And you guys are going together. great...
真不错
It is great.
真的很不错
Really great.
简直棒极了
Freaking awesome.
你们打算干什么
What are you guys doing?
今天是周五  也就是中国菜和老式游戏
It's friday night-- that means chinese food and vintage video games,
对不
Right?
老式这个词不足以形容我们的计划
Vintage doesn't even begin to describe what we have planned.
今夜  我们要玩经典的1980冒险游戏ZORK
Tonight, we are playing the classic 1980 interactive text adventure, zork.
而且是有漏洞的贝塔版
It's the buggy beta version.
强  ZORK呢
Wow, zork.
你们玩得开心
Well, you guys have fun.
再见
Yeah. see you guys.
再见  史都华
See you, stuart.
-霍华德  -什么
- Hey, howard? - yes?
带我去酒吧泡妞
Take me to a bar with women.
-真的吗   -对
- Really? - yeah.
好
Okay!
我先进去把内裤脱了
Let me just go inside and slip off my underwear.
为什么
Why?
如果今晚走运  我可不想被潜水侠内裤卡住
Well, if I get lucky, I don't want to be caught in my aquaman briefs.
来杯鸡尾酒  上面插把小雨伞
May I have a grasshopper with a little umbrella, please?
-不  不用了    -为什么
- No, he may not. - why?
我才不会和一个喝鸡尾酒
I'm not sitting here with a guy
还要插把雨伞的人坐一起
Drinking a grasshopper with a little umbrella.
好吧
Fine.
换巧克力马提尼
I'll have a chocolate martini.
又错了
Wrong again!
拜托 你知道我不醉得像
Come on, you know I can't talk to women unless
印度灯节里的灯那么旺就没法搭讪
I'm lit up like the hindu festival of dewali.
听着  洛城有很多酒吧
Look, There are plenty of bars in los angeles
可以让你点这些加巧克力的鸡尾酒和巧克力马丁尼
where you can order grasshoppers and Chocolate martinis,
但去那里已没必要点  因为没女人了
but you wouldn't have to because there are no women in them.
开窍了
gotcha.
我点杯白兰地亚历山大
I'll have a brandy alexander.
三剑客变成双飞侠了
All right, the three musketeers just became the dynamic duo.
我们不去勾搭那些女的?
Should we talk to some of these women?
不  现在还太早了
No. it's way too early in the night for that.
先让律师和运动员挑肥拣瘦  然后呢
See, first we let the lawyers and the jocks thin the herd, and then...
我们就直接上老弱病残的
We go after the weak and the old and the lame.
这就是你的秘诀
That's your system?
没错
That's my system.
如果看到有个带导盲犬的妞  她是我的
Oh, and if you spot a chick with a seeing eye dog, she's mine.
拜托
Oh, come on.
我感觉运动裤船长参加你的开幕式也无妨
I think it's nice that captain sweatpants showed up to your art opening.
如果他没碰所有奶酪的话更好
Yeah, it would have been nicer if he hadn't touched all the cheese.
时间还早
You know, it's kind of early.
你想喝点咖啡什么的吗
Do you want to maybe come in for some coffee or something?
好像咖啡晚了点啊
Oh, gee, it's a little late for coffee, isn't it?
你以为喝咖啡只是喝咖啡呢
Oh, you think "coffee," means coffee.
太纯洁了
That is so sweet.
来吧  我有脱咖啡因的
Come on. I think I have decaf.
太好了  史都华
Oh, good. stuart.
我听到你在说话
I thought I heard your voice.
你有空吗
Do you have a moment?
大概吧
Uh, yeah, I guess.
谢尔顿   我们有点忙
Sheldon, we're a little busy here, so...
你们干啥呢
What are you doing?
我们要喝咖啡
We're having coffee.
现在喝咖啡太晚了吧
Well, isn't it a little late for coffee?
没事  她有脱咖啡因的
It's okay. she thinks she has decaf.
我去找找
I'll just go look for it.
怎么了
What's up?
我刚才三小时都在网上蝙蝠侠
Well,  I've spent the last three hours in an online debate
坛子上辩论  想找你帮忙
In the dc comics batman chatroom, and I need your help.
那些小子很顽固的
Oh, yeah. those guys can be very stubborn.
什么话题
What's the topic?
我觉得如果蝙蝠侠的死是永久的
I am asserting, in the event that batman's death proves permanent,
那么第一任罗宾  迪克·格雷森
The original robin, dick grayson,
是他最合逻辑的继任人
Is the logical successor to the bat cowl.
谢尔顿   恐怕你错得太离谱了
Ooh. sheldon, I'm afraid you couldn't be more wrong.
什么
More wrong?
错是绝对化的  没有比较级的
Wrong is an absolute state and not subject to gradation.
当然有
Of course it is.
说番茄是蔬菜是小错
It's a little wrong to say a tomato is a vegetable.
说番茄是悬索桥是大错特错
It's very wrong to say it's a suspension bridge.
话说回来   迪克后来成了黑翼侠
But returning to the original issue, dick grayson became nightwing,
单独成英雄了
A superhero in his own right.
蝙蝠侠二代肯定是第二任罗宾  杰森·托特
Batman 2 has to be the second robin, jason todd.
肯定  肯定
Has to be? has to be?
我看你是故意挑衅
I hope you're being deliberately provocative.
我找到了
I found the decaf!
太好了
Oh, great!
给我一杯凉茶
Herbal tea for me, please.
酒保 来杯亚历山大鸡尾酒
Barkeep! Alexander me.
那边两个怎么样
How about those two?
不行 她们在吃花生呢
No... They're eating peanuts.
我又过敏  亲个嘴估计就得在西奈医院呆一周
And my allergies, one kiss would put me in cedars-sinai for a week.
角落里的那个呢
What about the ones in the corner?
有希望  很有希望
Possible. very possible.
你是想要那个戴颈圈的呢
Do you want the one in the whiplash collar
还是老眨眼睛的那个呢
or the one who keeps blinking?
我觉得眨眼睛的比较可爱
I think blinky's cute.
行  就这样
You got it, sir.
等等  我们就这样过去
Wait, so we just go over there?
别急
No.
我们不打无准备之仗
We have a little prep work to do.
把这个放进嘴里
Put this in your mouth.
我们经过她们身边  你打个趔趄
We walk past them, you stumble a bit.
我就说  抱歉  我朋友呢...
I say, sorry, my friend's had a little too much.
然后从你嘴里拉这个出来
And then I start to pull it out of your mouth.
然后说  他吃饱了撑的
And say, "a little too much fun."
懂了没
Get it?
她们会笑  我们也很开心
I mean, they're laughing. we're laughing.
接下来我们把姑娘们灌到
Then we get them up to about a .
血液中酒精浓度等级为15的时候
15 blood alcohol level,
告诉她们咱是大款
and tell them we're millionaires.
还有没有别的
What else you got?
看情况了
Depends.
你愿意坐我腿上  装做表演口技的傻子吗
Are you willing to sit on my lap and pretend to be a ventriloquist dummy?
不愿意
No.
我不能坐你腿上  你不懂规则
I can't sit on your lap. you don't know the routine.
抱歉  但你明显局限在前零点时期的DC宇宙了
I'm sorry, but you're obviously stuck in a pre-zero hour dc universe.
当然了
Of course I am.
去掉杀害蝙蝠侠父母的杀手乔·齐尔
Removing joe chill as the killer of batman's
明显剥夺了这个角色存在的理由
Parents effectively deprived him of his raison d'etre.
好吧
Okay.
你可以随便秀法语  但不能证明你是对的
You can throw all the french around you want, it doesn't make you right.
[法语]正好相反
Au contraire.
另外
Plus,
你忘了《无限危机》的故事情节
You're forgetting that the infinite crisis
又将乔·齐尔囊括进《蝙蝠侠传奇》中了
Storyline restored joe chill to the batman mythology.
我什么都没忘  而且我很厌恶你的语气
I am forgetting nothing and I resent your tone.
行
Okay.
谢尔顿  现在很晚了 我得去睡会儿
Look, sheldon, it's late. I've got to get some sleep.
那么 我赢了
So, I win.
没门  我是累了要休息
No, I'm tired.
那么  还是我赢了
So, I win.
好吧  你赢了
Fine. you win.
没错  我赢了
Darn tootin', I win.
佩妮  我今天真的很高兴
Penny, I really had a terrific time...
佩妮
Penny?
不  千万别叫醒她
No, no, no, no, no. don't wake her.
否则她会像金刚狼一样把你暴打一顿
She'll maul you like a rabid wolverine.
我喝的好象不是无咖啡因咖啡
You know, I don't think that was decaf.
等一下  这是不是你选的那张牌
Wait. is this your card or isn't it?
相信我  这是她们选的牌
Trust me. this was their card.
我还以为你很擅长泡妞
I thought you were good at this.
你总是讲怎么去酒吧泡妞
You're always talking about how you go to bars and meet women.
我经常做啊
I do, all the time.
那现在呢
Well, what happened?
我们在这坐了快一晚上
We've been sitting here all night and the longest
跟你谈话最长的却是打电话给你的老妈
Conversation you've had with a woman was when your mom called.
你就是要逼我说出口  对吧
Wow. you're just going to make me come out and say it, aren't you?
说什么
Say what?
你拖我后腿了
You're weighing me down.
我是只猎鹰  单飞时收获更好
I'm a falcon who hunts better solo.
行  我坐着  你去翱翔捕猎吧
Fine. I'll sit here. you take flight and hunt.
别逗了
Don't be ridiculous.
怎么能告诉猎鹰什么时候去捕猎
You can't just tell a falcon when to hunt.
实际上  可以的
Actually, you can.
周围都是猎物呢
There's whole sport built around it.
小猎鹰
Falconry.
闭嘴
Shut up.
叫上库萨帕里走吧
Let's just get koothrappali and go.
这小子真走运
Lucky bastard.
肯定是他口音的关系
It's got to be that stupid accent of his.
你好  我是孟买过来的桑贾伊
Hello. I am sanjay wolowitz from bombay.